Hubungi

maulinoakbar8@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yantrisnandra (LinkedIn)

dear-speedboat-145.notion.site/ Portofolio-33bf813e5d48496a85aca8 (Portfolio)

Keahlian Teratas

Selenium WebDriver
Data Processing
Bug Report

Languages

Bahasa Indonesia (Full Professional)
Bahasa Inggris (Professional
Working)

Certifications

Foundations of Software Testing and Validation

IT Support Google

Microdential Associate Data Scientist Associate - Kampus Merdeka

Quality Assurance

Publications

Personality Classification on Twitter Social Media using BERT

Yantrisnandra Akbar Maulino

Quality Assurance at Bumi Amartha Teknologi Mandiri | Katalon | Selenium | Postman | Cucumber | Jira | Agile |

Jawa Barat, Indonesia

Ringkasan

As a dedicated Quality Assurance Engineer with a Bachelor's degree in Informatics and cum laude honors (GPA 3.78), I have experience in ensuring software quality and performance. I have 1 year experience as a Quality Assurance Officer at PT Bumi Amartha Teknologi, and previously had an internship at Telkom Indonesia (1.5 years) and Binar Academy (4 months). My expertise includes API testing, automation, web application testing, mobile testing, performance testing, etc. I excel at creating efficient testing strategies, writing comprehensive test plans, and using advanced tools to solve problems. With strong analytical, communication and teamwork skills, I am excited to pursue further opportunities in Quality Assurance.

Pengalaman

Bumi Amartha Teknologi Mandiri Quality Assurance Oktober 2023 - Present (1 tahun 1 bulan)

Jakarta

- Develop test plan and test project timeline.
- Do internal unit test.
- · Do scenario test.
- Coordinate with user to do cycle scenario test.
- Develop SIT and/or UAT document

Binar Academy Quality Assurance Engineer Maret 2024 - Juni 2024 (4 bulan)

- Collaborate with PM, UI/UX, and Dev Team
- Create Test Case Management with Qase.io
- Create Bug Management with JIRA and Squash
- Create and Implementation of WEB, and API Automation Testing
- Create and Implementation API Automation Testing

Telkom Indonesia

Software Quality Assurance Engineer Intern

Februari 2022 - Juli 2023 (1 tahun 6 bulan)

Bandung, Jawa Barat, Indonesia

- Collaborate with Management, PO, Design team, and DEV team
- Make sure business requirement is ready for development (Backlog, Design, and Document)
- Create Test Case Management with Xray and Squash
- Create Bug Management with JIRA and Squash
- Create and Implementation of Android, IOS, WEB, and API Automation Testing with Katalon Studio
- Create and Implementation API Automation Testing With Newman Postman
- Create and Implementation Performance Testing (Stress Test and Load Test) with JMeter

Big Data Laboratory Telkom University

1 tahun 3 bulan

Data Science

Juli 2021 - Juli 2022 (1 tahun 1 bulan)

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia

One of Laboratory at Faculty Informatics, Telkom University.

Learn about Data Science fundamentals such as Machine Learning, Deep Learning.

Data Science Intern

Mei 2021 - Juli 2021 (3 bulan)

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia

Learn about Data Science fundamentals such as Machine Learning, Deep Learning and some other things about Data Engineering and Preparation.

Pendidikan

Universitas Telkom

Bachelor of Computer Science, Informatika · (2019 - 2023)

SMA Negeri 1 Cirebon

Science · (2016 - 2019)